Hello everyone and
welcome to English pod.
My name is Marco. My
name is Catherine and today
we have a very healthy
lesson for everyone.
We are going to
have a healthy food.
So we're going to the grocery
store and we're choosing
what food to buy.
You're going to hear
a lot of words about eating
right and eating healthy.
So let's jump into this dialogue
first and we'll be back in a
moment to talk more about it.
Okay, darling, I got
some pizzas, potato
chips, hot dogs and
lots of cheese. Oh John,
I thought we said we'd start eating
right. Remember, a new healthy lifestyle.
That's all junk food. Right, so what did
you get? Well, healthy food of course.
I got some whole wheat
bread, skimmed milk, fresh fish
and organic carrot.
Organic. What's organic?
Do we need organic
carrots? They were grown
without using any chemicals
that are harmful to our health.
And yes, John, we
need organic carrots.
Oh, so organic vegetables are the
green option, right? Yep, better for the
environment and better
for us. Wait a minute.
What's that? Donuts. Are they
organic donuts, Kelly? But I like donuts.
So it's a very popular
topic nowadays.
People want to eat light.
So why don't we take a look
at some of these words and
phrases now in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
The first kind of food we
have here is whole wheat
bread. So maybe you're
buying bread at the grocery store and you
see a number of different kinds of bread.
There's white bread. There's
rye bread. Well, we have
whole wheat bread, which is
maybe the healthiest option.
So it's made out
of wheat. All right.
So we have whole wheat bread.
Now, as you say, it's a type of bread that
uses wheat as its main ingredient. Right.
So it's made from wheat flour.
It's usually a brownish kind of bread.
That means the color
is brown, not white.
And it's healthier than white bread because
white bread uses that processed flour.
It does. It's processed and also uses a lot
more sugar. Okay. So whole wheat bread is
healthy option. And also
we are having skimmed milk.
All right. So as you know, when milk comes
out of the cow, it's very, very fatty.
There's lots of fat. And
so skimmed milk means
that when the dairy is
processing the milk, the
fat is taken away. So this is
one of the healthier kinds of milk.
You have fat free and skimmed
milk, which are the healthiest.
So when you buy normal
milk, what is that called?
Well, you have whole milk.
Whole milk. You also have 2% milk,
which is 2% fat. And then
skimmed milk and fat free milk.
Okay. Good. Now,
when we were talking
about the carrots, she said, you know
what? We also bought organic carrots.
So this is a very popular word
nowadays, organic vegetables,
organic carrots. What
does it mean if it's organic?
Well, in general, things that are organic
come from nature. But in food, things
that are organic
don't use chemicals.
So a lot of people are very
nervous about food that
comes from farms
that have pesticides or
chemicals on them. But
organic food is safe in this area.
There's no pesticides
or chemicals.
Okay. So what about
when you talk about
chickens or animals? They
also say it's an organic farm.
That means that they don't have
chemicals injected into them. That's right.
They're not stuffed with chemicals or given
chemical shots. And also the food that they
eat is real food. It's not like chemical
food to make them
fatter. Okay. Very good.
So organic foods. And you mentioned the
word chemicals a lot. So when we talk about
chemicals, we're talking about substances
that are artificial, right? That's right.
They're not organic. These
are things that are chemicals
that scientists come
up with to help make
food, for example, help
make fatter chickens or
to make greener vegetables.
And these are not natural.
These are man-made.
And chemicals
can also mean pesticides. So some sprays
or things that we put on plants to keep the
bugs away. And these are all things that
have been found to hurt human beings.
Yeah, I guess, for example,
when you are eating
something and you see in the box and it
says it has certain preservatives, those are
chemicals, right, that
help keep the food fresh
for a longer period of time. That's right.
Okay. So chemicals and that's the last word
that we have for you
on language takeaway.
Four keywords here
when we go back, listen to
the dialogue again and
we'll be back in a bit.
Okay, darling. I got
some pizzas, potato chips,
hot dogs and lots of cheese. Oh, John, I
thought we said we'd start eating right.
Remember, a new healthy
lifestyle. That's all junk food.
Right. So what to
do, get? Well, healthy
food, of course. I got some whole wheat
bread, skimmed milk, fresh fish and organic
carrot organic. What's organic? Do we need
organic carrots? They would grow in without
using any chemicals that
are harmful to our health.
And yes, John, we
need organic carrots.
Oh, so organic vegetables
are the green option, right?
Yep. Better for the
environment and
better for us. Wait a minute. What's that?
Donuts. Are they organic donuts, Kelly? But
I like donuts. All
right. We're back.
So now let's take a look
at three key phrases on
fluency builder fluency
builder. This first key
phrase is one that I think
was very, very common
in America in the
late 80s, early 1990s.
People in America have
been struggling with eating
healthy food and not
eating so much fatty food.
And so there was an
emphasis on eating right.
That's right to eat right.
Now, how do you eat right?
I mean, it sounds like you
want to eat with your spoon correctly. Now,
eating right is more about the kind of food
you eat. It's about not
eating pizza every day.
Pizza and hamburgers.
Okay. So we say eating
a balanced, we say
eating right involves having
a balanced diet. That
means eating vegetables
and grains and a little
bit of meat and not
so many sweets or oils. Okay. So that's
what it means when you are eating right.
So you have to eat right.
That means eating healthy.
That's right. Now, the
opposite. If you're not
eating healthy, that's
because maybe you're
eating too much junk food
and that's our next phrase.
Right. So junk
food is, you know,
junk garbage food. It's a, it's the kind of
food that is very unhealthy for you. Potato
chips, pizza, ice cream. It's all the best
kind of food. Yeah. But it's also the worst
for your body. So we
call it junk food. Okay.
So everything that's,
for example, fast food
is usually considered to be junk food. Yes,
it's high in oils and fats. Okay. So junk
food. And for the last phrase for today,
healthy lifestyle, healthy lifestyle.
And for the last phrase, we
are starting a healthy lifestyle.
So what does it mean
by a healthy lifestyle?
Well, we don't say life. We say
lifestyle because this is the way in which
a person lives. It's
your lifestyle. Okay.
So this involves exercise diet.
What kind of food you eat?
The way that you
work, do you get too
much sleep, not enough
sleep. So your lifestyle
is about the choices you
make in all parts of your life.
And so having a
healthy lifestyle.
As I said, it's not just about not eating
junk food. It's about running five miles
or trying to get
eight hours of sleep.
So it's important to
maintain a healthy lifestyle.
And usually in the
news, we always hear,
seriously, in the news,
we hear this phrase, not
healthy life, but
healthy lifestyle. Right.
So maybe somebody that
leads a dangerous lifestyle.
Maybe it does. Maybe it has
a job that's very dangerous.
That's right. Or an unhealthy
lifestyle, someone who eats one meal a day.
Okay. Very good. So those are key phrases
for fluency builder. Why don't we go back,
listen to the dialogue for the last time.
And we'll be back to talk
with you a little bit more.
Okay, darling, I got
some pizzas, potato
chips, hot dogs, and
lots of cheese. Oh, John,
I thought we said we'd start eating
right. Remember, a new healthy lifestyle.
That's all junk food. Right. So what did
you get? Well, healthy food, of course.
I got some whole wheat
bread, skimmed milk, fresh fish,
and organic carrot.
Organic. What's organic?
Do we need organic
carrots? They were grown
without using any chemicals
that are harmful to our health.
And yes, John, we
need organic carrots.
Oh, so organic
vegetables are the
green option, right? Yep. Better
for the environment and better for us.
Wait a minute. What's that? Donuts.
Are they organic donuts, Kelly?
But I like donuts.
All right, we're back.
So talking about healthy
food and healthy eating.
How healthy do you eat, Captain?
I think I eat pretty decently.
I try to eat a balanced diet.
Like I said earlier, I think a balanced
diet is a key to a healthy lifestyle.
I don't really eat fast food. Yeah, I try
not to eat too much meat or too much sugar.
What about organic stuff? Are you a big
fan of organic vegetables or organic meats?
I am. And this comes
from a part of the
dialogue we didn't cover.
One of the characters
says that vegetables
are the green option.
Okay. So trying to eat
organic food and think
about green is a part of thinking about the
environment. And so I think eating organic
vegetables is an important
part of caring about
the environment because
the more chemicals,
the more pesticides we put into the world,
the more harmful it is for the earth, for
animals and for ourselves.
That's absolutely true.
And it has become a
more popular aspect
around America and
Europe. People choosing to
go with organic vegetables. For example,
eggs that were grown on an organic farm.
And so it is the healthier
option. And obviously the
green option as we saw
in the dialogue. Okay.
So a very interesting
topic. We want to know
what your opinion is on it. Why don't
you come to our website, www.EnglishPod.
com and tell us if you are
a fan of the light or green
organic lifestyle or maybe
you just really don't really care.
Maybe you love junk food.
Let us know.
EnglishPod.com. All right.
We'll see you guys there. Bye.
(upbeat music)